Patryk Ptasiński

Email: resume@ipepe.pl

Phone: (+48) 510 355 151

Website: www.ipepe.pl

GitHub: @ipepe

Pragmatic Software Engineer with over a decade of diverse experience, specializing in optimizing legacy Ruby on Rails monolithic applications and complimenting them with Serverless or Microservice structures. Demonstrated management skills with quick learning ability and effective communication. Active in open-source community and proficient in security and performance optimization.

Education

Ruby Association Warsaw, Poland

Ruby Association Certified Ruby Programmer Silver version 2.1 (Credential ID RAS2119626933)

Nov. 2019

Polish-Japanese Academy Of Information Technology

Warsaw, Poland

Engineer degree in The Faculty of Information Technology

2012-2017

Speciality: Mobile Networking

Advisor: dr. inż. Michał Tomaszewski

Thesis: "Urban Navigation Based on WIFI Location Data"

Skills

Technical: Ruby on Rails JavaScript PostgreSQL React GraphQL JSON:API ElasticSearch Microservices

Serverless Monolithic Architecture Three.js NodeJS ActionCable WebSockets Azure AWS Bootstrap

Management: Mentoring Project Management Small Team Leadership Work Distribution Post Mortems

Work Experience

Visuality sp. z o.o. sp. k.

Warsaw, Poland

Lead Ruby on Rails Developer

2019 to Present

- Maintaining legacy code, developing complex algorithms, and optimizing system integration. Demonstrated proficiency in working within structured teams on diverse projects in sectors like accounting, invoicing, document processing, and business workflows for global clients. Key projects include enhancing backends for shopping apps, refining API applications, extending crawler code for document gathering platforms, rewriting server-side rendered views into JSON-API for recruitment apps, and working on optimizing architecture for fintech systems. Noted for problem-solving abilities, efficiency, and commitment to quality.
- Full Stack development: Ruby on Rails, React, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, JSON:API, Redis, ElasticSearch, Microservice and Monolithic Architectures.
- Related: AWS, Heroku, Rollbar, NewRelic, Github, Rubocop and Brakeman

Skriware (half year under DAFTCODE SP. Z O.O. in 2017)

Warsaw, Poland

Consultant for Ruby on Rails, WebGL (Three.is) and Azure Cloud Architecture

2017 to Present

Developed an interactive, Three.js-based online CAD editor for a company producing modular parts, enhancing
user engagement by providing an intuitive 3D design platform. Led the full-stack development of a complex
Ruby on Rails application, integrating innovative 3D printing solutions and IoT devices. Developed a cloud-based
slicer for 3D printers and robust algorithms for 3D model manipulation. Implemented a custom WebSocket-

based communication channel for real-time monitoring and control of 3D printers. Built the company's Azure infrastructure from the ground up, utilizing Docker and Azure Cloud services. Supervised project planning, resource allocation, and task distribution within the team.

- Full Stack development: Three.js, Ruby on Rails, React, NodeJS, ActionCable (WebSockets), PostgreSQL and Redis.
- Related: Azure Cloud, Capistrano, Microservices, Integration, Rollbar and GitLab.

In4mates sp. z o.o. sp.k.

Warsaw, Poland

Ruby on Rails Developer

2015

Lead Ruby on Rails Developer

2016 to 2017

- As the Lead Developer on a substantial accounting and business process project, I lead a team of 4 developers in creating a Business Process Manager (BPM) to automate and streamline our client's operations. This involved overseeing the full software development lifecycle, from concept design to deployment and post-deployment maintenance. We delivered a robust, user-friendly system and very modern (SPA) application for our client that satisfied his requirements.
- Full Stack development: Bootstrap, EmberJS, Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL.
- Related: Jenkins, Redmine, Capistrano, Docker, Vagrant, Integration, Monitoring and GitLab.

GAZ-SYSTEM S.A. Warsaw, Poland

Systems Administrator and T2 Helpdesk

2012 to 2014

- As a second-level on-site Helpdesk specialist, I diagnosed and resolved complex hardware and software issues, beyond the capability of first-level support. I effectively communicated with end-users and IT professionals, maintained detailed records of issues and resolutions, and leveraged this information to develop user guides and training materials, improving end-user understanding and competence using dedicated issue tracking platform.
- Administered Microsoft's SCCM for 2500 workstations, managing packages, applications, and enforcing compliance. Also managed on-site Active Directory for 600 users and computers, overseeing user accounts, access permissions, and group policies.
- Related: DevOps, Zabbix, PowerShell, VBScript, Acronis, Hardware Inventory, SLA, Microsoft Deployment Toolkit.

Digital Virgo S.A.

Warsaw, Poland

24x7 Helpline Support 2012

- Monitored and supported the operation of a Paid SMS Gateway, ensuring optimal performance and minimal disruptions. Examined logs and identified and reported errors, proactively addressing issues related to outgoing SMSes. Utilized Unix tools such as grep, tail, and head to effectively perform troubleshooting tasks. Worked in a demanding 24/7 support environment, understanding the significant financial implications associated with any interruptions in the gateway operations.
- Related: DevOps, SLA, Nagios, Scripting, Hardware Inventory and Software Licensing.

LACAN Technologies

Warsaw, Poland

OpenERP Developer 2010

- Developed and deployed various OpenERP modules to enhance business processes and productivity. Modules included a dynamic currency change tracking system, a CRM lead tracking tool, and a lead follow-up mechanism. Leveraged Python, XML, MySQL for development.